(ミナト)８本目の尾まで
封印が解放してしまうと➡
I worked it into the seal spell
so that I would appear within
your psyche,
俺が
お前の意識の中に出てくるよう➡
should the seal be broken to the point
you sprouted the eighth tail.
封印式に細工しておいたのさ。
なるべく
そうなってほしくはなかったが。
I really wanted to avoid that...
もうお前に
会いたくなかったしね 九尾。
Since I had no desire to see
you again...Nine-Tails.
でも…。
Then again...
成長した息子に会えるのは
少し楽しみでもあったから➡
I did look forward to seeing
my son as a young man.
So I'll call it even.
イーブンってとこかな。
Fourth Hokage!
四代目火影！
来い！ ズタズタにしてやる！
Come here!
I'll rip you to shreds!
Well, if that's the case,
I'll stay away.
ズタズタにするって言ってんのに
近づかないよ。
Right, Naruto?
もっともだろ？ ナルト。
Naruto... My name...
(ナルト)ナルトって 俺の名前。
How come the Fourth Hokage
knows my name?
どうして
四代目火影が俺の名前を？
Hm?
Well...I'm the one who named you.
ん？ だってお前の名前は
俺がつけたんだから。
You are my son, after all.
せがれなんだし。
せがれ… じゃあ 俺ってば…。
Son? Then...I'm...
Yes.
You heard me.
You're my son.
Fourth Hokage!
うん さっきも言ったろ
俺の息子だよ。
Loud fellow, isn't he?
Let's go somewhere quiet.
ハ… ハハハハッ…。
Third Hokage didn't tell you much
of anything, did he?
グォ～ッ 四代目！
I guess he wanted to suppress as much
information about Nine-Tails as possible.
If people had found out
you were my son,
うるさいね 後ろの。
you'd have been in danger.
少し別のところに行くよ。
Dad...
ヘヘッ。
Why did you seal the Nine-Tails
inside your own son?!
三代目は
何も言わなかったようだね。
Do you know what I went
through because of that?!
九尾にかかわる情報を➡
All the grown-ups looked
at me with contempt...
なるべく
伏せておきたかったんだろう。
And I couldn't make any friends.
息子とわかれば いろいろと
危険が降りかかるからね。
I wanted people to accept me,
父ちゃん…。
so I trained really hard
to become strong.
Then I met Iruka Sensei, and Kakashi Sensei,
and Pervy Sage...
うぅ…。
And I was happy because
they helped make me stronger!
なんで息子の俺に九尾なんか
封印したんだってばよ！
But because of that, a group called
the Akatsuki came after me,
おかげで俺ってば
すっげえ大変だったんだぞ！
so I had to train even more.
大人たちはみんな 俺のことを
冷たい目で見やがるし。
I got to be even stronger,
but the Akatsuki still killed my friends.
友達も なかなかできねえし。
だから俺 頑張って 頑張って➡
But...huh?
What am I saying?
みんなに認めてもらいたくって
すっげえ修業して強くなって➡
Damn it, am I supposed
to be happy or mad?!
I don't know anymore!
そしたらイルカ先生やカカシ先生
エロ仙人と出会えて➡
強くなることができて
嬉しかった。
Naruto... How old are you now?
でもそのせいで 暁なんてやつらに
狙われることになっちまって➡
Sixteen.
だからもっと修業しなくちゃ
なんなくなっちまって。
Wow... You're already
sixteen years old, huh?
せっかく
強くなれることができたのに➡
It must have been hard for you...
仲間が暁にやられて…。
I'm sorry, Naruto.
でも あれ？ 俺 何…。
あ～っ 嬉しいんだか
腹が立つんだか➡
I suppose after putting
my own son through so much...
もうわかんねえってばよ！
うっ…。
I have no right to act like
a father and apologize.
ナルト 何歳になる？
It's all right...already.
うっ… 16歳。
I'm the son...of the Fourth Hokage...
so I can handle it.
そうか もう16か。
いろいろ大変だったんだよな。
I sealed half of the Nine-Tails' chakra
inside of you,
ナルト すまなかった。
because I believed
you could control its power.
息子のお前につらい思いばかり
させてしまった俺が➡
Because you are my son.
父親ヅラして謝るのも違うかな。
And there is a reason why I did this.
いいよ もう…。
四代目の火影の息子なんだから➡
When the Nine-Tails attacked
the village sixteen years ago,
我慢する…。
I learned something.
What?
お前に九尾のチャクラを半分残して
封印したのは➡
There was a mastermind
who manipulated the Nine-Tails
to attack the village.
この力を使いこなすと
信じていたからだ。
Mastermind?
A powerful ninja at that.
俺の息子ならと…。
It would require a special kind of power
to go up against such an opponent.
I believe he will attack our village again.
なぜ わざわざそんなことを
したのかには理由がある。
今から16年前
九尾が里を襲ったとき➡
The Leaf Village
has already been destroyed.
わかったことがある。
何？
Yes... I watched from inside you.
あのとき 九尾を操り
里を襲わせた黒幕がいる。
You watched?!
黒幕？
それも かなりの力を持つ忍だ。
I know about Jiraiya Sensei too.
特別な力がなければ
とうてい 太刀打ちできない。
Then was it Pain who used the Nine-Tails
to attack the village before?
おそらく そいつは また里を襲う。
No... It wasn't him.
Then who was it?!
One of the Akatsuki.
もう 木ノ葉の里は
潰されちまったってばよ。
The one with the mask.
あぁ 見てた。 お前の中からね。
Back then...
he read through every action I took.
えっ… 見てたって…。
He's no ordinary ninja.
自来也先生のことも知ってるよ。
This man is probably just using Pain.
No! Pain had a grudge
against the Hidden Leaf!
それじゃ 前に九尾を使って
里を襲ったのは ペインなのか？
He said, long ago, his own village
was wiped out like ours!
いや違う そいつじゃない。
誰だってばよ？
That's right.
Because of that hatred,
he's being used.
暁の１人 面をしている男だ。
Used?! Someone strong like him?!
And what about
this mastermind masked ninja?
あのとき やつは俺の動きを
すべて見切った。
Why is everyone attacking the Leaf?
Perhaps as long as there is
a ninja system in this world,
ただ者じゃないよ。
there can be no peace.
おそらくペインは
そいつに利用されているだけだ。
Pain questioned you about peace...
違う！
ペインは木ノ葉に恨みを持ってた。
But finding the answer is difficult.
昔 同じように
自分たちの里もやられたって。
How would you confront this hatred,
in order to create peace?
そのとおりだ。
だから そこを利用された。
利用されたって!?
あんな強えやつが？
それに
黒幕だっていう面の忍まで。
In order to save something dear...
wars are waged.
なんで こんなに
木ノ葉ばかりが狙われるんだ！
この世に忍のシステムがある限り➡
As long as there is love,
there will be hate.
平和な秩序は
ないのかもしれない。
And some will take advantage
of that hatred.
ペインは
お前に平和について問うたが➡
This monster known as hate will
not die while there is a system of ninja.
答えを見つけるのは難しい。
It will give birth to more Pains.
((お前なら 平和を作るため
この憎しみと どう向き合う？))
It was Pain who killed Jiraiya Sensei,
but upon careful thought,
it can be said
that the chaotic world of the ninja,
which gave rise to Pain, is equally guilty.
大切なものを救おうとすることで
戦いが生まれ…。
To be a ninja is to confront hatred.
Each and every one of us battles hatred.
愛が存在し続ける限り
同時に憎しみが生まれ➡
Jiraiya Sensei trusted you to find
a way to end this hatred.
憎しみに忍が利用される。
この忍のシステムがある限り➡
憎しみというバケモノは
また新たなペインを生み出していく。
Still, I can't forgive Pain!
There's no way I can forgive him.
自来也先生を殺したのは
ペインだが➡
I know...
よくよく考えれば➡
Fourth Hokage... Tell me!
そのペインを生み出した
この忍の世の無秩序が➡
What should I do?!
先生を殺したも同然なのさ。
忍とは
その憎しみとの戦いなんだ。
FOURTH HOKAGE
You must find the answer yourself.
どの忍も
その憎しみと戦っている。
I do not have the answer.
If Pervy Sage and you don't know
the answer, how am I to know?!
自来也先生は
この憎しみを終わらせる答えを➡
Everyone expects too much!
お前に託したんだ。
I'm not smart!
だからって俺は ペインを許せねえ。
And I'm not a great ninja!
And...
許すことなんてできねえ。
I know you'll find the answer.
あぁ。
四代目 教えてくれ！
俺ってば どうしたらいい？
I have faith in you.
答えは自分で探すんだ。
その答えは 俺にもわからないよ。
Really?
You really believe I can do it?
エロ仙人や四代目すら
わかんなかったことが➡
To be a parent is to have
undying faith in one's child.
俺にできるわけねえだろ！
みんな勝手すぎるってばよ。
俺ってば 頭わりいし
そんなにすげえ忍者じゃねえし。
Now then... It's time for me to go.
それに 俺ってば…。
My chakra's fading.
お前なら
その答えを見つけられる。
Huh?!
No, wait...
I will rebuild the seal.
俺は お前を信じている。
However, this will be for the last time.
The Leaf can be rebuilt.
I'm counting on you...Naruto!
Thanks...Dad!
ほんとに…
ほんとに俺にそんなこと…。
どこまでいっても
子供を信じてるのが➡
親ってもんだからね。
さて 俺もそろそろ
行かなくちゃならないかな。
チャクラも薄れてきている。
えっ？ ちょっ…。
封印を組み直す。
だが これで最後だ。
くっ！
木ノ葉は まだやり直せる。
頼んだぞ ナルト。
《ありがとう… 父ちゃん》
Fourth Hokage
地爆天星から
這い出てくるとはな。
He is crawling out of
the Planetary Devastation.
なんて力だ…。
What incredible strength.
こうなったら 更に大きな…。
I must increase the size...
九尾が… 消えた。
The Nine-Tails...disappeared?!
His doubt is gone...
迷いが消えたか… 何があった？
What happened?
Does he now have control
over the Nine-Tails?
すでに九尾を制することが
できるというのか？
(小南)長門！
Nagato!
《九尾化したせいで
チャクラが乱れちまった。
The transformation into the Nine-Tails
disturbed my chakra.
仙術チャクラをストックしてた影分身も
消えちまってる。
It made me lose my Shadow Clone.
使える仙術チャクラは➡
俺自身に
残ってる分だけってことか》
I can only use the Sage Jutsu Chakra
I have left inside of me.
《すでに 仙人モードに入ったか…
タフなやつだ。
He's already in Sage Mode.
He's tough.
九尾の力 どれほどか
確認しておきたかったが➡
I had to confirm the extent
of the Nine-Tails' power,
まさか 地爆天星まで…》
but I never imagined he could stop
my Planetary Devastation.
(カツユ)プハーッ！
死ぬかと思いましたよ。
I thought I was going to die!
これって…。
What the...?
あっちは里のほう… あれは？
That's where the village is...
What happened?
You did it, Naruto, when you
were in the Nine-Tails state.
(カツユ)九尾化した
ナルト君がやりました。
《もしかして
ヒナタや木ノ葉の人たちを 俺が…》
I killed Hinata, and the people
of the Leaf Village?!
生きてる！
まだ ヒナタのチャクラが感じられる！
She's alive...
I can sense Hinata's chakra.
I was worried,
心配しました。
でも九尾化したナルト君の攻撃で➡
but no casualties resulted from
your assault
in the Nine-Tails state.
木ノ葉の人々に
被害は出ていません。
We were lucky.
運よくですが…。
I see.
うん。 そうか… よかった。
よかったってばよ。
Thank goodness. What a relief.
《ヒナタ : ナルト君…》
Naruto...
(ネジ)ヒナタ様！
(テンテン)致命傷は避けている。
でも すぐに治療しないと！
Lady Hinata!
Her injuries aren't fatal,
but she needs treatment immediately!
今 医療忍者を捜している！
I'll find some Medical Ninja right away.
((木ノ葉が暁に襲われた！
The Leaf Village is under attack
by the Akatsuki!
(わしゃ もう動けん。
はよう行ってくれ))
I cannot move anymore!
Hurry and go!
(ガイ)ここまでとは…。
I didn't know things were this bad.
(リー)こちらにも 怪我蛙です。
There's an injured toad here too.
そろそろ決着をつけよう。
It's time to settle this.
少しは 痛みを理解できたか？
Have you come to understand
a little of what pain is?
同じ痛みを知らなければ
他人を本当には理解できない。
Unless you know the same pain,
you cannot truly know another.
そして 理解をしたところで
わかり合えるわけでもない。
And even if you get to know others,
there can be no understanding.
That is the truth.
それが 道理だ。
Just like how it's useless
to chase after Sasuke.
お前が サスケを追いかけても
無駄なようにな。
Take me to where the real Pain is!
お前の本体のところへ
俺を連れていけ！
I want to speak to you face-to-face.
直接 話したいことがある。
Take me to where the real Pain is!
お前の本体のところへ
俺を連れていけ！
I want to speak to you face-to-face.
直接 話したいことがある。
Hmm... So you figured that out?
ほう… 本体に気づいたか。
Jiraiya Sensei and now you...
自来也先生も お前たちも
木ノ葉は なかなかやるものだ。
You Leaf Ninja are quite impressive.
However, our discussion is over.
だが 話は終わった。
Talking with you will change nothing.
今更 お前が何を語っても
何も変わらん。
Let me talk to him!
とにかく 話をさせろ！
Sage Mode...
仙人モード…。
It seems you can only throw two
of those nasty chakra shuriken.
あのやっかいな チャクラの手裏剣は➡
Isn't that so?
２発までしか
撃つことはできないようだな。
After that,
you will run out of Sage Mode!
しかも それで仙人モードは消える。
I guess I have no choice
but to fight you!
やっぱ 戦うしかねえみてえだな。
If both of your shuriken miss,
you shall lose.
もし その２発の手裏剣を外したら
お前の負けだ。
I will give you no more chances.
All that's left is to dodge your attack, and
then bring your half-dead body with me.
もう スキは与えない。
外したら最後
半殺しにして連れていくだけだ！
Too bad then...
I'll just look for the real Pain myself!
なら しかたねえ！
本体は自分で捜す！
But how?
I have an idea.
でも どうやって？
考えがある。
《こいつ
仙人モードで逆探知を…》
He reverse-tracked me using Sage Mode!
見つけたぜ！
Found you!
貴様…。
Bastard!
影分身の術！
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
よし 煙玉だ！
Now! Smoke Bombs!
おぉ！
Right!
Here comes the first shuriken.
《まずは １発目…》
Almighty Push!
神羅天征！
What?! He had already launched
the second one using Shadow Shuriken Jutsu?!
《なに!? ２発目を
影手裏剣で放っていただと!?》
His jutsu interval is five seconds!
《インターバルは ５秒…
これならいける！》
I can do this!
Four seconds to go!
《残り４秒…。
He was already standing by
with a Shadow Clone back then.
あの時すでに 影分身を
仕込んでいたとはな…。
Three more seconds
until I can use my next jutsu.
次の術発動まで ３秒…
だが ２発外したな…。
But he missed both shots...
It's over.
What?!
We still have two more seconds! Go!
He had this many Shadow Clones
transformed into rubble?!
One more second!
Zero!
He's now using Shadow Clones
as back up!
終わりだ！》
Someone like you who has no answer...
should just give up!
なに!?
But I have faith that
まだ ２秒ある！
there will come a time when
people can truly understand one another.
いっけ～！
And if I can't find the answer,
perhaps I will entrust you to find it.
《これほどの影分身を
がれきに変化させて！》
I know you'll find the answer.
I have faith in you.
《あと１秒！》
Only you can surpass
the Fourth Hokage.
I truly believe that.
ゼロ！
He withstood it... Impossible!
うわっ！
That jutsu cannot be thrown.
奥から 影分身を…。
I have five seconds.
This distance will work for me.
答えを持たぬ お前ごときが
あきらめろ！
Give up...
うぅっ！ うぅ…！
...on me giving up!
Rasengan!
((自来也 : だが いつかは➡
You're here.
人が本当の意味で
理解し合える時代が来ると➡
That must mean you defeated
the sixth Pain.
It doesn't matter who won or lost.
わしは信じとる。
答えが見つからんかったときは➡
What happened?
(その答えを
お前に託すとしようかのう))
In any case, I'm on my way
to see the real Pain.
((お前なら
その答えを見つけられる。
Please don't follow.
I want to go alone.
(俺は お前を信じている))
Alone?!
((カカシ : 四代目火影を超える忍は
お前しかないと➡
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"The Two Students"
There's something I want
to confirm with him.
(俺は そう信じてるからだ))
GUY'S ROOM
Yamato's Room has been
renamed Guy's Room!
Hello, this is your idol...
Might Guy!
耐えた… だと!?
Our guest today is the pride of
the Leaf Village,
kunoichi Hinata Hyuga!
H-Hello.
Aw come on.
Don't be so bashful on my program.
《あの術は 投げ飛ばせない…
５秒… この距離ならいける》
O-Oh umm...
She is extremely introverted and shy.
Her hobby is pressed flower art.
She loves cinnamon rolls and
sweet bean jam?
俺が あきらめるのを…。
Forget the script!
I'll just ask you things
I'm curious about.
That's what a live,
youthful interview is about!
あきらめろ！
Huh?!
By the way, Hinata...
You've really matured lately.
Let me guess, you're in love, right?
螺旋丸！
(スティング)帰ってきたんだって。
(ローグ)何の話だ？
- W-Well...
- All right, then!
(スティング)７年前に失踪した
フェアリーテイルの主要メンバー。
Look straight into that camera
and say what's in your heart!
I-I can't...
(ローグ)興味ないな。
ウソをつくなよ ローグ。
あれほど憧れたナツさんだぜ。
(ローグ)昔の話だ。